Finding aid for the Nathan Pritikin papers LSC.1628
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Testimonials: (65th) Birthday Book; Creative Tributes; Posthumous Tributes-Articles
  - Media: Posthumous
    - Newspaper reports - Autopsy reports. (Box 23)
      (See also: Separate scrapbook)
    - Lay periodical reports. (Box 23)
    - Posthumous articles. (Box 23)
    - Posthumous testimonials. (Box 23)
    - Sympathy cards (in back of box). (Box 23)
- Athletes/Pilots
  - Athletes and Pritikin diet: I. Physicians re Pritikin
    - Bassler, Dr. Tom. (Box 24)
    - Reply to Tom Bassler: Running magazine, 1981. (Box 24)
    - Reply to Tom Bassler: AMJA, July 1981. (Box 24)
    - Sports Physicians. (Box 24)
    - Guten, Dr. Gary. (Box 24)
    - Mirkin, Dr. Gabe. (Box 24)
    - Sheehan, Dr. George. (Box 24)
    - Subotnick, Dr. Steven. (Box 24)
  - Athletes and Pritikin Diet: II. Individual Athletes
    - Athletes - Heart disease patients. (Box 24)
    - Robert de Castella. (Box 24)
    - Rolet de Castella. (Box 24)
    - Nicholas de Castella. (Box 24)
    - Jim Fixx's death: Tragic and unnecessary. (Box 24)
    - Alberto Salazar. (Box 24)
    - David Scott. (Box 24)
    - Jack Stevens. (Box 24)
    - Stan Cottrell. (Box 24)
  - Athletes and Pritikin Diet: III. Triathlon, (October 1982)
    - Participants. (Box 24)
    - UC Davis testing. (Box 24)
    - Triathlete diet/drink. (Box 24)
    - Tri-Athletes. (Box 24)
    - Public relations. (Box 24)
    - Results. (Box 24)
    - Press coverage/publicity. (Box 24)
  - Athletes and Pritikin Diet: IV
    - Runners' Study Questionnaire. (Box 24)
  - Athletes: Runner's World - Columns, Correspondence
    - Runner's World - columns and related correspondence. (Box 24)
    - Runner's World - Miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 24)
    - Donald Monkerud article (Runner's World, )., 1976 (Box 24)
  - Athletes and Pritikin Diet: Miscellaneous
    - National Association for Sport and Physical Education. (Box 24)
    - Correspondence re "Pritikin Promise." (Box 24)
    - Runners and other athletes on Pritikin program. (Box 24)
    - Athletes using diet or similar diet. (Box 24)
    - Athletes: Correspondence. (Box 24)
  - Airlines: Miscellaneous
    - Airlines: Delta, Pan Am, Northwest. (Box 24)
    - Scandinavian Airlines System. (Box 24)
    - TWA. (Box 24)
    - Food: American Airlines. (Box 24)
    - United Airlines diet: Arnold, Valente, Dr. Harper. (Box 24)
  - Aircraft Companies
    - Becker, Dr. Robert / Boeing Company. (Box 24)
    - Martin Marietta Aerospace. (Box 24)
  - Flight physicians and pilots
    - Aircraft companies; food service. (Box 24)
    - Pilots. (Box 24)
    - Airline physicians. (Box 24)
    - Aviation Medical Bulletin. (Box 24)
    - Aerospace Medical Association. (Box 24)
    - Harper, Dr. C.R. (Box 24)
    - Canadian Airline Pilots Association. (Box 24)
    - Jim Irwin - Astronaut. (Box 24)
    - Harvey Watt Company - Dr. Charles Gullett. (Box 24)
- Pritikin Programs - Centers
  - Pritikin Programs: Information Requests
    - Hand-out set () from Pritikin International., 1982-83 (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: Available programs/material. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: Following Pritikin diet in restaurants/travel. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: Diet brochures; diets for children, athletes. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: Diet/food questions. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: I. Medical questions, blood lipids. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: II. Medical questions, miscellaneous. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: Food preparation/recipes. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: Recommended reading/tapes. (Box 25)
    - Hand-outs: Miscellaneous inquiries. (Box 25)
    - Survey of Letters (Santa Barbara). (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Program Audiotapes, Videos and Teleconference
    - Riseman, Katz & Mayer: Video tape production. (Box 25)
    - Electronic arts intermix video: "The Pritikin Way." (Box 25)
    - Symposium International - Noel Reede (teleconference, audio & video tape). (Box 25)
    - Pillar Productions: Proposed Pritikin Program video. (Box 25)
    - Pritikin tapes for sale. (Box 25)
    - Proposed tapes. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Better Health Program: Program Materials I
    - Original 12-week program. (Box 25)
    - Introductory lectures. (Box 25)
    - Food demonstrations. (Box 25)
    - Material for program participants. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Better Health Program: Program Materials, II
    - Later PBHP Program and administrative material. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Better Health Program: Plans, Promotion, Personnel
    - Plans for PBHP, I. (Box 25)
    - Plans for PBHP, II (Nature's Preference, a publicly held corporation). (Box 25)
    - Newspaper ads, brochures, announcements. (Box 25)
    - East Coast. (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 25)
    - Bentley, Steve. (Box 25)
    - Brotherton, Richard. (Box 25)
    - Delgado, Nick. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Better Health Program: Alumni Organizations
    - Alumni activities. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Longevity Center 1-Day Health Seminars. P.M., and Fitness Center Programs
    - Longevity Center One-day Health Seminars. (Box 25)
    - Pritikin P.M. - non-residential program - Santa Monica. (Box 25)
    - Pritikin Fitness Centers. (Box 25)
    - Weight Loss program. (Box 25)
  - Pennsylvania Pritikin Center - Downingtown
    - Downingtown, Pennsylvania Center. (Box 25)
    - Participants' book. (Box 25)
    - Pennsylvania Center material. (Box 25)
  - Florida Longevity Center
    - Early Florida Longevity Center. (Box 25)
    - Bauer, Dr. Robert. (Box 25)
    - Lehr, Dr. David. (Box 25)
    - Florida Center. (Box 25)
  - Hawaii Pritikin Center
    - Maui Center. (Box 25)
  - San Diego Longevity Center
    - Kaiser Permanente Hospital, San Diego. (Box 25)
    - UC San Diego: Extension program. (Box 25)
    - San Diego: Longevity Center. (Box 25)
  - Hospital Plans: Live-in and Better Health Programs
    - Interested hospitals. (Box 25)
    - Administration/marketing. (Box 25)
    - (Pritikin Program): Dr. Harold Snow, Utah. (Box 25)
    - Dr. Leonard Braudo. (Box 25)
    - Dr. Daniel Mason. (Box 25)
    - Employees. (Box 25)
    - De La Ronde, Henrotin, etc. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Programs - Marketing
    - Meeting Minutes. (Box 25)
    - Nathan's early vision: "Aids for Your New Lifestyle." (Box 25)
    - Possible finance sources. (Box 25)
  - Medically-Related Business Ventures, Miscellaneous
    - United Medical Corporation. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Restaurants
    - Pritikin Pantry. (Box 25)
    - Pritikin-sponsored restaurants: Miscellaneous correspondence notes. (Box 25)
  - Pritikin Cruises
    - Pritikin Cruise (Caribbean):, May 24, 1980. (Box 25)
    - Cruises, etc. (Box 25)
- Correspondence: Patients/Non-Patients (A-R)
  - Box no.25 contains 51 files representing Nathan Pritikin's extensive correspondence with Center patients as well as with numerous non-patients. (Box 27)
- Correspondence: Patients/Non-Patients (S-Z); Correspondence Answered by Staff
  - Individual correspondence., (18 files) (Box 28)
    (Continuation from Box no.25)
  - Foreign Correspondence - Consultations
    - [No further description available]. (Box 28)
  - Dissatisfied Patients
    - [No further description available]. (Box 28)
  - Mish-mash Correspondence
    - "Babblers." (Box 28)
    - "Nudnicks" (nags). (Box 28)
    - "Funnies" (?). (Box 28)
    - Post Office persistence. (Box 28)
  - Correspondence answered by Nell Taylor. (Box 28)
  - Correspondence Answered By Nan Bronfen (aka Nan Cisney; Nan Smith). (Box 28)
  - Correspondence Answered by Claire Trazenfeld. (Box 28)
  - PLC Staff: Consultations. Correspondence
    - Byron Weston, M.D. (Box 28)
    - PLC Staff: Consultations, Correspondence. (Box 28)
- Media
  - Lists of Articles By or About Nathan Pritikin/and Program
    - [No further description available]. (Box 29)
  - Publicity Master List: (Newspaper Articles, Magazines), 1969; 1976-1981
    - [No further description available]. (Box 29)
  - Personal Documents/Notes
    - American Federation of TV & Radio Artists. (Box 29)
    - Pritikin's ideas for media. (Box 29)
    - Pritikin's notes - media. (Box 29)
  - Press Conferences; Press Releases
    - [No further description available]. (Box 29)
  - Interviews
    - Interviews: TV-radio transcripts. (Box 29)
    - Interviews. (Box 29)
  - Cartoons and Humor
    - [No further description available]. (Box 29)
  - Syndicated Newspaper Articles
    - Los Angeles Times syndicate. (Box 29)
    - Possible syndicated column. (Box 29)
  - Newspapers
    - Chicago Tribune - Jon Van, (June 10, 1984). (Box 29)
    - National press coverage, initial. (Box 29)
    - National press coverage, I. (Box 29)
    - Local press coverage - Santa Barbara area. (Box 29)
    - Media: Los Angeles and California area. (Box 29)
    - National press: Magazine section; Food section. (Box 29)
    - USA Today. (Box 29)
    - Wall Street Journal () - Pritikin replies to "100,000 Killed., November 1981 (Box 29)
    - Foreign press coverage. (Box 29)
    - Downingtown opening. (Box 29)
  - Media: Lay Periodicals
    - Lay periodical reprints. (Box 29)
    - New York Times - "Styles America", (1983). (Box 29)
    - Newsweek, (1981). (Box 29)
    - New York Magazine, (1976). (Box 29)
    - Media Queries, (1978). (Box 29)
    - Family Health, (July, August, 1981). (Box 29)
    - The Humanist (editor Lloyd L. Morain:, May/June 1981; September/October 1984; January/February 1989). (Box 29)
  - Media: Radio/TV
    - "Today" Show, (November 8, 1983). (Box 29)
    - Susskind Show, (October 1978). (Box 29)
    - CBS "60 Minutes", (1977). (Box 29)
    - Radio Syndication. (Box 29)
    - Media: Local radio/TV - Santa Barbara area. (Box 29)
    - TV/radio - 1. (Box 29)
    - TV/radio - 2. (Box 29)
  - Foreign TV - Interviews
    - Canadian Broadcasting System. (Box 29)
    - Interviews (foreign). (Box 29)
  - Publicity:, 1969: 1976-1985; (11 Files)
- Media: Public Relations - Newsletters
  - Media correspondence: Periodicals, etc.
    - Radio-TV: Correspondence, memos, etc. (Box 30)
    - Foreign press coverage (initial) correspondence. (Box 30)
    - Media correspondence - periodicals. (Box 30)
    - Media correspondence - Miscellaneous. (Box 30)
  - Writers - Publishers
    - Otis Chandler (L.A. Times). (Box 30)
    - Benno Isaacs. (Box 30)
    - Theodore B. Wood. (Box 30)
    - Columnists. (Box 30)
    - Columns (potential). (Box 30)
    - Writers (favorable). (Box 30)
  - Public Relations Firms
    - Berkhemer & Kline. (Box 30)
    - Doyle, Dane & Bernbach. (Box 30)
    - Fleishman-Hillard. (Box 30)
    - Ruder, Finn & Rotman. (Box 30)
    - Jack Ryan. (Box 30)
    - Public relations: Miscellaneous. (Box 30)
  - Clippings (Burrelle's)
    - [No further description available]. (Box 30)
  - Longevity Center Newsletters I - LRI Lifespan
    - Newsletter LRI:, 1976. (Box 30)
    - Lifespan:, 1977-1980. (Box 30)
  - Longevity Center Newsletters II - The Center Post, (1980-1989)
    - 9 Files. (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters/fact sheet - Santa Monica. (Box 30)
- Australia
  - Correspondence - General. (Box 31)
  - Margaret Gee. (Box 31)
  - Restaurant interest. (Box 31)
  - Pritikin Diet cookbooks. (Box 31)
  - Posthumous tributes. (Box 31)
  - Australia: Tours
    - March, 1980. (Box 31)
    - (cancelled)., March, 1981 (Box 31)
    - October, 1982. (Box 31)
  - Medical Professionals
    - Medical professionals, miscellaneous. (Box 31)
    - Dintenfass, Dr. Leopold. (Box 31)
    - Schneideman, Dr. Ian. (Box 31)
      (See Pritikin Research Foundation studies, Box no.32)
  - Ross Horne
    (See also Ross Home book, "The Health Revolution", in back of box)
  - Pritikin Lifestyle Association
    - Miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 31)
    - Gerry Jukes, newsletter editor. (Box 31)
    - Dr. Lynn McMahon, President. (Box 31)
  - Australia: Pritikin Lifestyle Association (Newsletters, Publicity)
    - Newsletters. (Box 31)
    - Publicity flyers. (Box 31)
  - Newspaper series/clippings on Pritikin Diet
    - Series on Pritikin diet. (Box 31)
    - Clippings on books and diet. (Box 31)
- Food Products
  - Legal aspects of food endorsements by Pritikin organizations
    - Products endorsed; legal opinion. (Box 32)
    - Frank Mergaman. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Food Development: Potential Distributors, Investors, Food Sources, etc.
    - Distributors, investors, etc. (potential). (Box 32)
    - Food services (potential). (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Food Development: R & D. Miscellaneous
    - Institute of Applied Technology (I.H. Goldenfield). (Box 32)
    - Richard Brotherton: Retort packaging of Pritikin foods. (Box 32)
    - Soluble Products Corp: Pritikin beverage meal. (Box 32)
    - Sprouted grains - Vitamin B-12 experimentation. (Box 32)
    - Cheeses/dairy products. (Box 32)
    - Natural flavors. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Food Development: R & D, Batter-Lite Foods, Incorporated
    - [No further description available]. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin food products (Miscellaneous) - Not Marketed
    - Richard Berk - baked pastries. (Box 32)
    - Reisman Company pretzels. (Box 32)
    - RJR Foods, Incorporated project. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Foods Products Distributor: Health Valley Distribution Company
    - [No further description available]. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Foods Products, Marketed
    - List of marketed Pritikin food products. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Food Products, Not Marketed: Hunt-Wesson Foods, Incorporated
    - Hunt-Wesson foods project. (Box 32)
    - Hunt-Wesson; Dr. Walter Clark. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Food Products, Marketed: Interstate Bread, Muffins
    - Pritikin bread inquiries; "Live Longer Now" complaints. (Box 32)
    - Interstate bread: Distributors. (Box 32)
    - Interstate bread: Label. (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Food Products: Interstate Bread - Correspondence
    - Interstate" Brand: Correspondence (Pearlstein, et al.). (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Foods Marketed: Thompson Kitchens, Incorporated
    - James M. Lillis, president: Correspondence, (1982-1984). (Box 32)
  - Pritikin Foods Marketed: Thompson Medical Company
    - Thompson Medical Company: Dan Abraham. (Box 32)
    - Thompson Medical Company: Edward L. Steinberg, M.Sc. (Box 32)
  - Breads: Miscellaneous (Australia, etc.)
    - Foreign: Riga Bakery Pty. - Australia. (Box 32)
    - Bread - other companies. (Box 32)
    - Foods. (Box 32)
- Pritikin Research Foundation (aka Nathan Pritikin Research Foundation: Longevity Research Institute)
  - Scientific press articles: Publication from the NPRF
    - Publications - NPRF. (Box 33)
    - Manuscripts. (Box 33)
    - Pritikin Bibliography. (Box 33)
  - Scientific press by Pritikin and/or Staff. I. Articles and Abstracts
    - Articles/Abstracts - Pritikin and/or Staff:, 1981-1986. (Box 33)
    - Articles/Abstracts - Pritikin and/or Staff:, 1975-1977; 1979. (Box 33)
  - Scientific Press by Pritikin and/or Staff: II. Correspondence re Articles
    - [No further description available]. (Box 33)
  - PRF-Mt. Sinai Conference:, 1984
    - Program. (Box 33)
    - Arrangements. (Box 33)
    - PRF Dinner honoring Sen. George McGovern: 4-28-84. (Box 33)
    - Press releases - press conference. (Box 33)
    - Press coverage. (Box 33)
  - PRF 5th Annual Educational Conference & Advisory Board meeting
    - Arrangements. (Box 33)
    - Program. (Box 33)
    - Publicity. (Box 33)
    - Abstracts/Talks. (Box 33)
    - Advisory Board participation and meeting. (Box 33)
    - Conference attendance, 1981. (Box 33)
  - PRF 4th Annual Educational Conference & Advisory Board Meeting
    - Arrangements. (Box 33)
    - Program. (Box 33)
    - Speakers' abstracts. (Box 33)
    - Publicity. (Box 33)
    - Advisory Board participation and meeting. (Box 33)
    - Advisor Hans Weber's write-up of meeting. (Box 33)
  - Longevity Research Institute 3rd Annual Educational Conference and Advisory Board meeting
    - Program. (Box 33)
    - Speakers' Abstracts. (Box 33)
    - Publicity. (Box 33)
    - Arrangements. (Box 33)
    - Audience invited. (Box 33)
    - Advisory Board participation and meeting. (Box 33)
    - Advisor Hans Weber's write-up of meeting. (Box 33)
  - Longevity Research Institute 2nd Annual Educational Conference and Advisory Board meeting
    - Arrangements. (Box 33)
    - Program. (Box 33)
    - Correspondence with speakers for program. (Box 33)
    - Publicity. (Box 33)
    - Audience invited and attended. (Box 33)
    - Advisory Board participation and meeting. (Box 33)
    - Advisor Hans Weber's write-up of meeting. (Box 33)
  - Longevity Research Institute 1st Annual Educational Conference and Advisory Board Meeting I
    - Arrangements/Program. (Box 33)
    - Invited physicians and other guests. (Box 33)
    - Replies to questionnaire. (Box 33)
    - Advisory Board meeting. (Box 33)
    - Advisor Hans Weber's write-up of meeting. (Box 33)
  - Longevity Research Institute 1st Annual Educational Conference/Adv. Board Meeting II
    - Transcripts. (Box 33)
  - Physician Education Goals
    - [No further description available]. (Box 33)
  - CME Credit: Educational Conferences
    - Accrediting institutions. (Box 33)
    - Physicians receiving credits. (Box 33)
- Pritikin Research Foundation
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal I: General Information
    - Study administration; planning meetings, memos, forms. (Box 34)
    - Research project/research paper updates. (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified notes. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal II: Miscellaneous Studies
    - Allergy. (Box 34)
    - Athletic performance/runners' deaths. (Box 34)
    - Arthritis. (Box 34)
    - Compliance, longer term. (Box 34)
    - Health care costs (Kaiser Permanente, San Diego). (Box 34)
    - Hearing disorders. (Box 34)
    - Osteoporosis. (Box 34)
    - Perimenopause study. (Box 34)
    - Periodontal study. (Box 34)
    - Psoriasis. (Box 34)
    - Tinnitus. (Box 34)
    - Toxemia in pregnancy - Dr. Morton Sacks. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal II: Miscellaneous Studies
    - Visual problems. (Box 34)
    - Intervention trials (Box 34)
      (See also: Natchitoches Study)
    - Chronological vs. biological age. (Box 34)
    - Nutritional adequacy. (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous studies. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal II-A: Loma Linda University
    - Loma Linda: Dr. David Abbey, (August 6, 1980). (Box 34)
    - Loma Linda University School of Health. (Box 34)
    - LLU Research Service. (Box 34)
    - LLU Analysis: 893 LRI patients. (Box 34)
    - LLU Analysis: 893 LRI patients. (Box 34)
    - Diehl-Fraser: Two papers (3-14-80). (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal III: Heart, blood, coronary angiograms
    - Plasmapheresis study; Miscellaneous. (Box 34)
    - Plasmapheresis study: Richard Brotherton project report (, PL Technology, Cholesterol Apheresis)., 1985 (Box 34)
    - Plasmapheresis study: Dr. Prince's group. (Box 34)
    - Central Florida cardiology group. (Box 34)
    - Coronary Angiogram study. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal III-A: Heart, Blood, Miscellaneous
    - 65 patient study: Posthumous presentation of paper by Ilene Pritikin. Moscow, June 1985. (Box 34)
    - Dr. Leopold Dintenfass (Australia). (Box 34)
    - Hypertension. (Box 34)
    - Coagulation Time. (Box 34)
    - Brigham Young University: Coronary Risk Factors. (Box 34)
    - Blood lipid studies. (Box 34)
    - Coronary risk factors of Pritikin Diet (Brigham Young). (Box 34)
    - Platelet aggregation. (Box 34)
    - Estradiol study. (Box 34)
    - APO-A & B Study. (Box 34)
    - LRI - YMCA Study. (Box 34)
    - 2.3 Diphosphoglycerate, effect of dietary fat on levels of. (Box 34)
    - Post-M.I. Patient, Diet. (Box 34)
    - Memos, etc. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal IV: Cancer
    - Breast cancer. (Box 34)
    - Breast cancer protocol -Dr. Morton Sacks. (Box 34)
    - Colon cancer. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal V: Diabetes
    (See also: DISEASES: Diabetes, Box no.8)
    - Diabetes studies. (Box 34)
    - Prospective study: Effects of high carbohydrage, high fiber, low fat diet on juvenile onset diabetes. (Box 34)
    - Diabetes study: California Council on Wellness. (Box 34)
    - Heber, Dr. David - study by. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal VI-A: Natchitotches, Louisiana
    - State of Louisiana/Governor Edwards correspondence. (Box 34)
    - Herman K. Beebe. (Box 34)
    - Pritikin correspondence/schedule/notes. (Box 34)
    - PRF funding. (Box 34)
    - Dr. C. B. Ellis, Dr. Donna Ellis: Project Life Study Coordinators. (Box 34)
    - Study: Staff/volunteers. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal VI-B: Natchitoches, LA
    - Progress reports. (Box 34)
    - Compliance survey/other results. (Box 34)
    - Formal study design: PRF statements. (Box 34)
    - Control city for study. (Box 34)
    - Dietary programs/exercise guidelines. (Box 34)
    - Formal study design: Consultations/research. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal VI-C: Natchitoches, LA
    - Governor's kick-off dinner. (Box 34)
    - Community outreach forms/plans/efforts. (Box 34)
    - Medical community outreach/response. (Box 34)
    - Nursing homes. (Box 34)
    - Substance abuse patients; Briscoe Center. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal VI-D: Natchitoches, LA
    - Medical Tribune article/Pritikin response. (Box 34)
    - Calvin Trillin: "New Yorker." (Box 34)
    - Media coverage. (Box 34)
    - Subsequent Natchitoches-type community programs. (Box 34)
  - PRF Studies: Study Proposal VII: Captain align/Mutiny on the Bounty Re-enactment,, Using Pritikin Diet, 1983
    - Captain R.W. Ware correspondence. (Box 34)
    - Diet prepared by PRF for voyage. (Box 34)
    - Captain Bligh - open boat voyage: Publicity. (Box 34)
- Pritikin Research Foundation - Longevity Research Institute
  - Correspondence with Individual Advisors and Trustees
    - Applebaum, John J., D.D.S. (Box 35)
    - Barry, Jack. (Box 35)
    - Balke, Dr. Bruno. (Box 35)
    - Bassler, Dr. Thomas J. (Box 35)
    - Becker, Dr. Robert. (Box 35)
    - Bjorksten, Dr. Johan. (Box 35)
    - Brady, John G., Ph.D. (Box 35)
    - Burkitt, Dr. Denis. (Box 35)
    - Belsky, Dr. Marvin. (Box 35)
    - Coffin, Dr. Lewis. (Box 35)
    - Cogan, Dr. James R. (Box 35)
    - Crook, Dr. William. (Box 35)
    - Cranton, Dr. Elmer. (Box 35)
    - Currier, Dr. W.D. (Box 35)
    - Dick, John. (Box 35)
    - Dobrin, Dr. Leo. (Box 35)
    - Dunker, Dr. John S. (Box 35)
    - Falik, Louis H., Ph.D. (Box 35)
    - Fields, David S., Ph.D. (Box 35)
    - Glenn, Paul. (Box 35)
    - Gnekow, Dr. William. (Box 35)
    - Hellerstein, Dr. Herman. (Box 35)
    - Kostrubala, Dr. Thaddeus. (Box 35)
    - Leibovitz, Dr. Maury. (Box 35)
    - Leidesdorf, Arthur. (Box 35)
    - Leonard, Jon. (Box 35)
    - MacKenzie, Jack. (Box 35)
    - Magnin, Cyril. (Box 35)
    - Margolis. Henry. (Box 35)
    - Morain, Lloyd (Box 35)
      (See also Box no.27, Media, Lay Periodicals, The Humanist)
    - McClatchie, Samuel, FRC pathologist. (Box 35)
    - Morrow, Dr. Robert. (Box 35)
    - Morse, John Boit. (Box 35)
    - Perlsweig, Leon. (Box 35)
    - Poniatoff, Alexander. (Box 35)
    - Powers, Dr. Hugh. (Box 35)
    - Pullen, R.W. (Box 35)
    - Puska, Dr. Pekka (Finland). (Box 35)
    - Scharffenberg, Dr. John A. (Box 35)
    - Stenn, Dr. Frederick. (Box 35)
    - Tarzian, Mary. (Box 35)
    - Trowell, Dr. Hugh. (Box 35)
    - Trowell, Dr. Hugh: Diseases that may regress on LRI regime. (Box 35)
    - Wallace, George. (Box 35)
    - Waxman, Lionel. (Box 35)
    - Weber, Dr. Hans. (Box 35)
    - Wheaton, Dr. Jerrold. (Box 35)
- Pritikin Research Foundation/Longevity Research Institute: Minutes, Other Records
  - Letters to Trustees and Advisory Board members (Box 36)
    (See also Box no.31)
  - PRF Correspondence (Box 36)
  - Pritikin Research Foundation/Nathan Pritikin Research Foundation: By-laws, Objectives. (Box 36)
  - Pritikin Research Foundation: Minutes. (Box 36)
  - Pritikin Research Foundation: Financial Statements. (Box 36)